<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-09T09:49:34+02:00</updated><id>//</id><title type="html">devit</title><subtitle>The Devit conference</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What to expect from DEVit 2017</title><link href="/blog/what-to-expect-from-devit2017" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What to expect from DEVit 2017" /><published>2016-10-06T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2016-10-06T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/blog/what-to-expect-from-devit2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/what-to-expect-from-devit2017">&lt;p&gt;DEVit 2017 is already in the making. We are making a big shift this year and we are more than excited to share all the details with you! So let’s dive in, what will we see this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Mega Speakers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we are thrilled to bring speakers from all over the world! You see, the budget can set some boundaries for events, but as the conference grows so do budgets. Thus, in 2017 we will bring multiple, speakers from all over the world and of course the US. Expect the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Single Track&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having tested the 2-track main event format in the previous years we gained a good understanding of how it flows. The thing is that speakers were antagonizing while many attendees couldn’t choose between two talks happening the same time (damn you paradox of choice). This is not what we want. This year we switch to a single track. We want a frontend dev to watch a backend speaker and vice versa. This is what being 360 is really about and what the intention of the conference is. To cross-pollinate from different expertise and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Two-day conference&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, Workshops! Yes, we became a two-day conference but there is an important detail here. The second day is fully dedicated and committed to providing the best workshop experience. Last year’s workshops were an experiment and you provided us with a lot of feedback. This year they will be full hands-on experience and there will be a variety of all-day workshops down to one-hour ones, where you will dive into hot topics. In other words, we will have a lot and amazing workshops for you to choose from!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##DEVit week&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We covered most of the info about the event. DEVit weekend will definitely be an unforgettable experience. Now let’s talk about DEVit week. If you have never visited Thessaloniki you should know that there is a vibrant community over here full of energy and creativity, running meetups, events, and conferences(pun intended)! DEVit week will be full of these festivities organized by this amazing community. The only left to say is “get ready to feel the vibe”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Amalia Vradi</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="devit2017" /><category term="conferences" /><category term="development" /><summary type="html">DEVit 2017 is already in the making. We are making a big shift this year and we are more than excited to share all the details with you! So let’s dive in, what will we see this year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Greece has come to finally make it to the Software Development conferences map</title><link href="/blog/how-greece-came-to-make-it-to-software-development-conferences-map" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Greece has come to finally make it to the Software Development conferences map" /><published>2016-07-09T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2016-07-09T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/blog/how-greece-came-to-make-it-to-software-development-conferences-map</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/how-greece-came-to-make-it-to-software-development-conferences-map">&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-made-it&quot;&gt;We made it!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Originally posted from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.attheo.do/2016/05/14/How-Greece-Came-To-Make-It-To-Software-Development-Conferences-Map/&quot;&gt;Thanos Theodoridis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/@softwaregarden&quot;&gt;Patroklos Papapetrou&lt;/a&gt; couldn’t cut it to the chase any better; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/greece-made-finally-software-development-conferences-patroklos&quot;&gt;Greece has finally made it to the software development conferences map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next months, at least six big conferences are about to take place in various big cities of Greece. And how we came to this is not an event but rather a process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all it appears we’ve reached the critical mass of professionals with interest in such kind of events. I know there have been conferences and symposiums for years before but these were mostly positioned towards academics. The past few years we’ve been seeing more and more conferences with talks on subjects born out of the everyday struggle in the industry. And more and more people seeing value in them. It appears the professional software developers “guild” is coming strong in a period of severe economic turbulence in the country. Great news for both professionals and companies seeking to absorb them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year being my second getting involved in the organization of &lt;a href=&quot;http://devitconf.org&quot;&gt;DEVit&lt;/a&gt;, I am pretty sure about at least one thing. Organizing and executing a conference is no easy job. It involves planning, managing and coordinating, almost orchestrating I might say, lots of stakeholders down to the minute. Definitely not a task for team of two or three. So how have we come to have six conferences in various cities in Greece? As I see it, great effort comes out of the communities orbiting around common interests. Software developers are one of the very few professions, maybe second to doctors and medical professionals, that favor meet-ups, get-togethers and synergy so much. And if you look closely, you will discover yourself there has been an almost Darwinian evolution in the shaping of communities interested in technology the past few years. Look no further and you will discover that behind every major conference there are excited volunteers from local communities like &lt;a href=&quot;http://skgtech.io&quot;&gt;SKGTech&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://greecejs.org/&quot;&gt;GreeceJS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://http://agilegreece.org/&quot;&gt;Agile Greece&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jhug.gr/&quot;&gt;Java Hellenic User Group&lt;/a&gt; and even local meet-ups. We grew as a few colleagues having beers every once in a while, to slowly inviting others and meeting periodically. Then we started giving talks to each other. We got to know our colleagues, we nurtured synergy and grew our meet-ups to packed rooms. And when we discovered there are quite many like us with the same lust for knowledge and networking, we took it one step further. We started organizing conferences!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, wait. There’s another thing I learned being part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://devitconf.org&quot;&gt;DEVit’s&lt;/a&gt; organizational committee. Conferences need money to pull through! Like, lots of them. So there is yet another tipping point in the process. Suddenly there was money. This is one of the most interesting parts of the process you see because you would expect total financial draught from a country who owes 175% of its GDP. So where did money come from? Three things: international sponsors, local startups and local businesses cultural shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take it one by one. How international companies like GitHub, Microsoft, Mozilla and others came to trust a newly-found conference to sponsor? Honestly, I am not so sure. But if I was to bet my money on it, I’d say because they somehow recognized this exact process we are talking about here. Thankfully, we were lucky to have some local fellows, some “silent heroes” that have worked for that recognition to happen. You know who you are guys and thank you so much. In any case, back to sponsoring 101, what sponsoring an event gets you in exchange is essentially exposure. And exposure only makes sense if it comes in magnitude. You need the critical mass and you need the communities’ support to achieve that. Throw in the fact that these events are also still one of their kind, and you’ve got your ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A part of me wants to believe that they also heard a word or two from attendees or speakers of previous years events, but maybe that’s not true just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, there are local startups too. Great people from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.skroutz.gr&quot;&gt;Skroutz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.workable.com&quot;&gt;Workable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.taxibeat.com&quot;&gt;Taxibeat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.e-food.gr&quot;&gt;E-Food&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://netscan.co&quot;&gt;Netscan&lt;/a&gt; and others who were once members in our meet-ups and founding members of the communities that followed, felt the need to give back. Support the ecosystem. Endorse the cause. Do they care about the exposure? Not so much I believe. They are just our buddies who acknowledge the effort and want to stand their ground by us in the battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, and frankly quite interestingly, we have the local businesses. Organizations like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intrasoft-intl.com/&quot;&gt;Intrasoft International&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ots.gr/&quot;&gt;OTS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beta-cae.com/&quot;&gt;Beta CAE Systems&lt;/a&gt; suddenly are willing to support small but admirable efforts from local communities. Why? Do they care about the exposure? How an e-government software company like OTS can benefit from its exposure to a Web Developers conference? It can’t. It’s not exposure they seek for. The big ships are suddenly trying to find new ways to navigate through the rough waters. You see, there is a talent shortage in Greece. Smart people are fleeing to companies abroad and budget cuts do not allow big organizations to invest so much in training junior people. They came to understand that they need to get closer to the “pool”, not through their corporate austere hiring workflows but in the form of pitching brochures in swag-bags and friendly delegates in sneakers mingling with the attendees flock. Sounds like wolves disguised as sheep, but not really. They straightforwardly want to hire people. Conferences like &lt;a href=&quot;https://voxxeddays.com/thessaloniki/&quot;&gt;Voxxed Thessaloniki&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://devitconf.org&quot;&gt;DEVit&lt;/a&gt; are great channels to attract talent. And, be no fool, big organizations like these are great opportunities for career growth in a country whipped by huge unemployment percentages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in terms of how I see it, that’s the story or the process that got us here. In a timespan of five years we’ve gone from ten member local meet-ups to international events with hundreds of people. Excitingly, the process is constantly hitting milestones along the roadmap and continuously evolving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-process-is-still-ongoing-its-going-forward-we-are-all-going-forward&quot;&gt;The process is still ongoing. It’s going forward. We are all going forward.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As a bonus, here are X reasons to attend at least one of the conferences taking place in Greece:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s affordable&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At around 60€-80€ we get a full day of great presentations, lots of coffee, swag and free meal!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The atmosphere is relaxed&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Greeks are known for being laid-down and relaxed people. We are open hearted, friendly and due to our climate the whole world wants to vacate in our country.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay close to the bleeding edge&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;With speakers coming from tech leaders like Facebook, Mozilla, Microsoft, GitHub and other top-notch companies, you will learn about tools, techniques and best practices straight from the horse’s mouth.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grow your network&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Greek cities are relatively small and most people know each other. This creates a very friendly environment in which you can get introduced to new great connections with common interests, make new friends, find a co-founder or potentially hire talent for your company.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will probably be there&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;‘Nuff said.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Thodoris Bais</name><email>thodoris.bais@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="greece" /><category term="conferences" /><category term="development" /><summary type="html">We made it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DEVit 2016 Retrospective, planning for the future</title><link href="/blog/2016-retrospective-planning-for-2017" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DEVit 2016 Retrospective, planning for the future" /><published>2016-05-30T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2016-05-30T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/blog/2016-retrospective-planning-for-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016-retrospective-planning-for-2017">&lt;h2 id=&quot;devit-2016-is-over&quot;&gt;DEVit 2016 is over!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh what a blast DEVit 2016 was! No matter how exhausted we were we could not stop the rush of endorphins that flooded our bodies for days after. You see, we, and by ‘we’ I’m referring to everyone that was at DEVit, managed to make a difference, we participated in making history for our community, for our country. We have successfully &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.attheo.do/2016/05/14/How-Greece-Came-To-Make-It-To-Software-Development-Conferences-Map/&quot;&gt;positioned Greece in the global landscape of international conferences&lt;/a&gt;, helped make DEVit a sustainable yearly conference and had such an amazing time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know we messed a few things up, I’ll get to them one by one in a bit, but what prevailed in the end was our amazing attitude, passion and determination to have a good time. Your amazing vibes gave us all the motivation we needed to continue with DEVit, scale it up and bring you an even more amazing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-feedback&quot;&gt;Your feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said before we did mess a few things up… At registration we definitely dropped the ball, at our retrospective meeting we dived deep into all the various reasons why this happened, they were a lot and we had to deal with multiple failures even on some of our contingency plans. Be rest assured that we didn’t take this lightly, we have already devised a new game plan and will work hard towards making the registration process as fast and seamless as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also know that most of you didn’t get too excited with the talks we had… We hear you loud and clear and we’ll make sure to have an even more strict vetting process for next year’s speakers. We will leverage our, now even bigger, network of communities throughout Greece, speakers from the two previous DEVits and pick up every stone we can turn so we can book and verify the best and most challenging speakers for DEVit 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than those 2 major fails we have made over 50 bullet points on things that we should be improving, tweaking and fixing. You see, DEVit is a community organized event and everything that you see about DEVit comes out of our free time. However this community is not comprised by hobbyists, we are professionals with decades of experience in project management, web development, design, marketing and all the arts, crafts and sciences that can make this work. Combine that with our excess amounts of OCD and perfectionism and you can be rest assured that you are up for a big treat for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-good-parts&quot;&gt;The good parts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough with the ugly, let’s dive into the good parts! First of all, we got bigger, this year we had more attendees, in total 420 people were at the conference compared to 350 for DEVit 2015! We managed to get top notch sponsors as well that honored us with their support and made such a demanding conference possible. Effectively bringing awareness to the fact that there is a tech community out there, active, strong, united.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The networking was immense as well, having the most educated, passionate and curious developers in one place in big quantities gives ground for new friendships, partnerships and deals. Our speakers were extremely satisfied with the organization and will actively help us spread the word for DEVit and connecting us with even more world class speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got really excited with our workshops, we tried them as an experiment but didn’t expect the kind of participation and interest you would show! This gave us a lot of ideas for what to prepare for you next year, but more on that in a little bit…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’d like to close by thanking all the volunteers that made this year’s DEVit a reality, the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shesharp.org/&quot;&gt;SHESHARP&lt;/a&gt; team was integral to making things happen to the point were they are now co-organizers of the event! The awesome folks from SKGTech and everyone else that helped us this year, credits page coming soon, promise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-ahead-2017-here-we-come&quot;&gt;Looking ahead, 2017 here we come!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the problems of DEVit 2016 was that we started planning too late, we practically got started mid January 2016, barely 4 months before the event. That amount of time was ridiculously small considering everything that happens for DEVit happens at our free time… That will no longer be the case…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have decided on the dates of DEVit for the next three years and have started planning for all of them from now, right the next day when DEVit 2016 finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DEVit 2015 was an experiment, we didn’t have any historical data, there was no other technological event of that scale organized anywhere in Greece, we had never organized such a big scale event before… We came through…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DEVit 2016 was verification. We made sure that the numbers observed in 2015 were not a fluk and we could reliably verify them, attendees, sponsors, ticket price, venue, catering, all the major and minor parts that comprise a conference of that scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DEVit 2017 will be all about scaling! Oh boy what do we have in store for you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-day-conference&quot;&gt;Two day conference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, we’re becoming a two day conference, holding the main event with 2 tracks on Saturday 20th of May and a full day of workshops on Sunday the 21st. We were amazed by your interest in workshops, challenging workshops, and how much you valued them. So we’re dedicating a full day for workshops in a multi-stage environment, hosting everything from full-day workshops down to 3, 2, or 1 hour sessions; whatever and as much time the presenter will need to convey their experience to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A two day conference will require a conference dedicated hotel as well,
so we have already started making the arrangements to fully book a hotel for the days of the conference so all of you coming from out of town can stay along with your peers and speakers where the DEVit’s heart will beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-devit-week&quot;&gt;The DEVit Week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DEVit has grown big, it’s so big it needs it’s own whole week of events, festivities and rock’n’roll! DEVit 2017 will start from the previous week with unique events organized by local communities, accompanied by our international speakers who will stay with us all week so they can imprint and share their experiences in the more intimate environment of small local meetups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will also make sure there are enough parties, drinks and fun so you can all claim that you lived through the DEVit experience and “proudly survived”! It won’t be easy, beware!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opening-up&quot;&gt;Opening up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source is strong within us, as such, that’s how we want DEVit to be. We want to share our knowledge, experience, know-how and most importantly numbers so you can pick it up and create an international conference of your own! It definitely won’t be easy but if you know the average cost of an attendee or how much catering will cost you, we’re confident you’ll be one step ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the following weeks and months, we’ll be releasing all our financial numbers, profit (thankfully we didn’t lose any money) and how we plan on using it for next year’s DEVit conferences… So aspired community leaders and conference organizers stay tuned as we’ll open up everything…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-administration&quot;&gt;New administration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the shocks we had to endure for DEVit 2016 was the fact that one of the two  co-organizers of the conference could no longer participate and help, thus leaving me (Hi! I’m &lt;a href=&quot;http://thanpol.as&quot;&gt;Thanasis&lt;/a&gt; by the way!) as the sole organizer for DEVit 2016. That’s no job for one man, especially when you do it on your free time. So things had to change moving forward…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m proud and excited to announce the two organizers for DEVit 2017 and onwards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alkistics&quot;&gt;Amalia Vrady&lt;/a&gt; is a core member of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shesharp.org/&quot;&gt;SHESHARP&lt;/a&gt;, a local community group organizing tech events and promoting the participation of women in the tech world. She is a student at the University of Macedonia at Applied Informatics and is at her last year before graduation. Amalia will run all operations of the conference making sure everything ticks at the right moment and everyone has what they need to do their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_margaritis&quot;&gt;Konstantinos Margaritis&lt;/a&gt; is a core member of &lt;a href=&quot;http://skgtech.io&quot;&gt;SKGTech&lt;/a&gt; and co-organizer of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Thessaloniki-Node-js-Meetup/&quot;&gt;local Node.js group&lt;/a&gt;. He is the head of engineering at &lt;a href=&quot;https://goodvid.io/&quot;&gt;goodvidio&lt;/a&gt; taming AWS instances, automation and microservices. Kostas will lead the Speakers committee and be the head of Spirit and awesomeness departments, to ensure we-keep-it-real &lt;strong&gt;boom&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teams behind the people are &lt;a href=&quot;http://skgtech.io&quot;&gt;SKGTech&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shesharp.org/&quot;&gt;SHESHARP&lt;/a&gt; who have wholeheartedly made DEVit a reality with all their hands on! One of the things we’re proud of is exactly that, how many people, from different walks of life, with so diverse experiences and agendas, have all come together, united, to achieve a single goal, educate, empower and unite the Greek tech community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-you-can-help&quot;&gt;How you can help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like we said, DEVit is a community organized event, you, me, everyone is the community! We do not have any entry procedures, the only thing you have to do is raise your hand and say “I want to help”. You can then pick your working group based on your experience, passion or were you’d want to be trained on, operations, web design &amp;amp; development, corporate, sponsors, speakers, administration… We are looking for any kind of experience, from students up to established professionals to take the lead (hello marketing!). DEVit has so many departments that you’ll definitely find a fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t think this twice, hop in our &lt;a href=&quot;http://devitconf.org/#slack-invite&quot;&gt;slack channel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@devitconf.org&quot;&gt;shoot us an email&lt;/a&gt; or just &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/devitconf&quot;&gt;wave at us on twitter&lt;/a&gt; and let’s make history together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Thanasis Polychronakis</name><email>thanpolas@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="retrospective" /><category term="devit2016" /><category term="devit2017" /><summary type="html">DEVit 2016 is over!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">All about DEVit</title><link href="/blog/all-about-devit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All about DEVit" /><published>2016-02-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-02-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/all-about-devit</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/all-about-devit">&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-few-words-about-the-devit-conference&quot;&gt;A few words about the DEVit conference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;DEVit is a 360° Web Development Conference (Frontend, Backend, DevOps, Mobile). The idea is that we want to get our attendees out of their comfort zone and cross pollinate all arts and crafts that make today’s World Wide Web possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second year for DEVit and we aim to make it, once again, an &lt;strong&gt;unforgettable experience&lt;/strong&gt;! Last year’s DEVit took place next to the sea at the awesome venue of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.makedoniapalace.com/&quot;&gt;Makedonia Palace Hotel&lt;/a&gt; and attracted over &lt;strong&gt;350&lt;/strong&gt; people. It was a blast for every speaker, attendee and DEVit volunteer. We had such a great time and highly valuable pieces of knowledge were disseminated towards all directions. You can have a look at last year’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://devitconf.org/2015/&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; and awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/131931106@N08/sets/72157653228840910/&quot;&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s DEVit is happening on &lt;strong&gt;Friday the 20th of May, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;, in an even bigger venue, &lt;a href=&quot;http://profile.helexpo.gr/profile/en/thessaloniki%20vellidis&quot;&gt;Vellidio Conference Hall&lt;/a&gt;. Thessaloniki is at its best during May and speakers can enjoy Greece’s sunshine and the deep blue seas during the weekend following the event, they are just an hour away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;absence-of-women-speakers-on-2015-lineup&quot;&gt;Absence of women speakers on 2015 lineup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year’s lineup was one of our weakest points and it has been discussed thoroughly during our retrospectives. Diversity was a big issue but we have already turned the page and we are aiming to &lt;strong&gt;achieve a 50/50&lt;/strong&gt; split on our &lt;strong&gt;2016 lineup&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;regarding-expenses&quot;&gt;Regarding expenses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer to pay &lt;strong&gt;traveling and accommodation&lt;/strong&gt; expenses for every speaker except if their company wishes to cover any or all of them.  In that case we’d gladly add them as &lt;strong&gt;sponsors of the DEVit conference&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;honorarium&quot;&gt;Honorarium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are a &lt;strong&gt;community backed conference&lt;/strong&gt; a honorarium is something, currently, not affordable for us. However, we hope it will be feasible to offer it from 2017 and onward. What we do cover apart from the accommodation and travel expenses is the &lt;strong&gt;dinner on Thursday night&lt;/strong&gt; (May 19th), &lt;strong&gt;transportation&lt;/strong&gt; from/to the airport and a &lt;strong&gt;mini city tour&lt;/strong&gt; with a local guide (speakers and DEVit staff) that takes place prior to the speakers dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grab your chance to be part of DEVit by applying to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1WOPx_vhoXwR4HBYp3HVAkr5OkV-ysiYbWz4WINsCR_Q/viewform?c=0&amp;amp;w=1&quot;&gt;CFP&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Konstantinos Margaritis</name><email>kostas@devitconf.org</email></author><category term="blog" /><category term="retrospective" /><category term="honorarium" /><category term="inclusion" /><category term="diversity" /><category term="devit2015" /><category term="about" /><category term="mea culpa" /><summary type="html">A few words about the DEVit conference</summary></entry></feed>
